Guide to the Erasmus Hall Records 1325–1989 (bulk circa 1775–1975) MS 201
New-York Historical Society
- "Archives of Erasmus Hall High School"
  - Lott, Jeremiah (1776–1861)
    - Itinerary of a trip taken by Jeremiah Lott through New Jersey and Pennsylvania, undated, 1915 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Lott Family)
      Interesting for its detailed observations about the people and places visited on the journey. n.d.
      This is a typewritten ms. only, accompanied by a cover letter from John J. Snyder dated 1915. Snyder made this transcription and states in his letter that the original is being returned, but it is not among the papers in the Erasmus Hall Archives.
    - [July Fourth oration], 1804, 1911 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Lott Family)
      Original manuscript of the Fourth of July oration delivered in Flatbush in 1804, accompanied by printed copy of the address, prepared in 1911 by local historian John J. Snyder.
    - Lease, 1845–1855 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Lott Family)
      Lease dated Sept. 29, 1845, in which Lott leased to Thomas Sullivan, Builder, two lots on Wyckoff St. in the City of Brooklyn for five years, $20 per annum. Signed by Lott and Sullivan, with red wax seals.
      Also, receipts from City of Brooklyn for payment of real estate taxes, 1845–55.
    - Minutes, Board of Supervisors of Kings County, 1831 May 23 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Lott Family)
      Minutes taken by Jeremiah Lott at a meeting of the Board of Supervisors of Kings Co., 23 May 1831. 3 p. The writing is not very easy to read, as it was obviously written in a hurry.
    - Indenture, 1777 December 27 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Lott Family)
      22 x 25 ½" indenture on parchment, Dec. 27, 1777, made between "Cornelius Van Duyn of Kings County in the Province of New York Farmer" and "James Savage of the City of New York Gentleman," in which the former deeded for 356 pounds a tract in New Utrecht, in Kings Co., to the latter. Apparently the deed was not executed, for it was not signed by either party or the witnesses. It does, however, have the bold signature of Jeremiah Lott on the reverse.
    - The Heidelbergh Catechism, or Method of Instruction, in the Christian Religion, as the same is taught in the Reformed Churches and Schools of Holland. Translated for the Use of the Reformed Protestant Dutch Church, of the City of New-York (New York: John Holt), 1764 (Offsite-box RC-16)
      Book from his library, with his autograph on t.p. and p. 46.
    - Het Nieuwe Testament... (Amsterdam), 1696 (Offsite-box RC-16)
      Inscribed inside rear cover, "Jeremeas Lott syn boek Anno 1788." With bookplate of Dr. John L. Zabriskie (1831–1895) of Flatbush.
  - Lott, John A. (d. 1878)
    - [Resolution on passing of Hon. John A. Lott], 1878 July 27 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Lott Family)
      Original, black bordered resolution passed by the Trustees of Erasmus Hall Academy July 27, 1878, to express sorrow at the passing of Hon. John A. Lott, LL.D. Signed with the autographs of John M. Ferris, Henry Lyles Jr., and Jacob V. B. Martense, Committee; and John J. Vanderbilt, Chairman: and Abraham I. Ditmas, Clerk Pro-tem.
  - Lott House
    - New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission, Designation Report, Hendrick I. Lott House (1940 East 36th Street, Brooklyn), 1989 October 3 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Hendrick I. Lott House)
      Also available online at http://s-media.nyc.gov/agencies/lpc/lp/1705.pdf.
  - Low, Dr. J. Herbert (EHHS principal, 1917–1934)
    - Letters, printed programs, photographs, etc., regarding Dr. Low, second principal of EHHS, [1917–1934] (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Dr. J. Herbert Low, principal, EHHS, 1917–1934)
    - Dr. J. Herbert Low's Musical Compositions, undated (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Low, Dr. J. Herbert—Musical compositions)
    - "Faculty Dinner to Dr. J. Herbert Low... In Honor of his Fifteen Years as Principal of Erasmus Hall High School" [copy 1], 1932 April 30 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Dr. J. Herbert Low, principal, EHHS, 1917–1934)
    - "Faculty Dinner to Dr. J. Herbert Low... In Honor of his Fifteen Years as Principal of Erasmus Hall High School" [copy 2], 1932 April 30 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder EHHS—Faculty Dinners (2 folders))
    - Photograph, undated (Offsite-box RC-9b, Folder Dr. J. Herbert Low over-sized photograph)
      Photograph in matte, about 11 x 14", showing Dr. Low sitting at roll-top desk in his later years a principal.
    - Certificate of Merit awarded to J. Herbert Low by the Board of Education, City of Brooklyn, for general excellence as a pupil, in School No. 35, 1878 January (Offsite-box RC-10b, Frame Certificate of Merit, J. Herbert Low)
      Framed, under glass, about 14 ½ x 16 ½".
  - Mack, Eli T. (Erasmus Hall Academy principal, 1863–1874)
    - Holograph letter regarding elevation of the "standard of instruction in this institution", 1868 November 17 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
    - Holograph letter tendering his resignation as headmaster, 1873 December 23 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
      With cover letter, dated Dec. 23, 1873, signed by H(enry) S. Ditmas.
  - Malamud, Bernard (1914–1986)
    - Two letters, 1959, 1967 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Autographs)
      Noted author, wrote The Fixer, 1966.
      • Letter dated March 18, 1959, on stationery of Oregon State College, written and signed by Malamud to Miss Ellen Batchelor, 625 Ocean Ave., Brooklyn.
      • Letter dated May 26, 1967, from Cambridge, Mass., typed and signed "Bern." (Also to Ellen Batchelor.) "It pleases me that you think highly of the book. Some women have told me they found it hard to take."
  - Martense family
    - Bill of sale to Garret Martense of Flatbush for "A Negro Wench named Peg", 1797 February 16 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Martense Family)
      7 x 12" document, dated 16 Feb. 1797, in which "we John Blake and James Groenendyke of the town of New Utrecht, County of Kings & state of New York, for and in consideration of the sum of Thirty pounds," sold to Garret Martense of Flatbush "A Negro Wench named Peg." Signed by the grantors, and by two witnesses: D. Cortelyou, Rutgert A. Van Brunt.
  - Mastin, Florence Ripley (poet, 1887?–Feb. 23, 1968)
    - Florence Ripley Mastin papers, undated (Offsite-box MS-27)
      Correspondence, holograph manuscripts, and published books produced by Miss Mastin, a well-known poet who also was a teacher at Erasmus Hall.
  - Mathematics Medals
    - Copies of tests given for Mathematics Medals, 1924–1942 (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Awards)
  - McNeill, John F. (EHHS principal, 1934–1965)
    - Personal files and correspondence (box 1 of 4), [1934–1965] (Offsite-box MS-19)
    - Personal files and correspondence (box 2 of 4), [1934–1965] (Offsite-box MS-20)
    - Personal files and correspondence (box 3 of 4), [1934–1965] (Offsite-box MS-21)
    - Personal files and correspondence (box 4 of 4), [1934–1965] (Offsite-box MS-22)
    - Newspaper clippings, memorabilia, etc., 1934–1970 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Dr. John F. McNeill, principal of EHHS, 1934–65 (2 folders))
      • 1934 (Apr. 17) Invitation to attend the installation of Dr. John F. McNeill as Principal.
      • 1934 (?) "To John F. McNeill: An Appreciation." Booklet autographed by the whole faculty of EHHS
      • 1945 (Oct. 24) "We Welcome Our First Citizen Back." The Dutchman, v. 32, no. 2 (3 copies)
      • 1954 (Sept. 14) "Dr McNeill's Air Career Ends." Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Sept. 14, 1954.
      • 1959 (March 21) Testimonial Luncheon for Dr. John F. McNeill: invitation (3 copies), newspaper clipping, seating plan, song sheet, and his letter of thanks.
      • 1964: Poem written by Florence Ripley Mastin for Dr. McNeill's retirement (used in the Erasmian).
      • 1965 (May 22) Testimonial Luncheon in honor of Dr. John F. McNeill: invitation, program with seating plan, New York Times clipping.
      • 1965 (May 31) "Dr. McNeill Receives Honors; Lauded at Special Luncheon." The Dutchman, v. 56, no. 9 (8 copies).
      • 1970 (March) "Dr. John F. McNeill Dis at 75." The Dutchman, v. 71, no. 5 (3 copies).
      Addenda:
      • 1945 (May 17) Letter sent by Lt. Col. McNeill from Dalhart Air Field, thanking Miss Lila Grossman for sending copies of The Dutchman.
      • Many photographs of Dr. McNeill are included.
    - Photograph, undated (Offsite-box RC-9b, Folder Dr. McNeill)
      Photograph in matte, about 12 ½ x 16". This photograph was used in the Chronicles, v. 2 (1937).
  - McMahon, Aline (1899–1991) (movie actress and Erasmus alumna)
    - Autographed photograph inscribed to Erasmus Hall High School, 1935 March (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Autographs)
  - Meteorological Records
    - Meteorology of Flatbush, 1826–1842 (Offsite-box RC-17, Volume Meteorology of Flatbush [spine: blank])
      Large folio volume with manuscript weather observations recorded each day pursuant to instructions from the Regents of the State of New York.
    - Meteorological observations taken at Erasmus Hall Academy, 1826–1857 (Offsite-box RC-17, Volume Meteorological observations taken at Erasmus Hall [spine: "Meteorological Register, Vol. 2"])
    - Franklin B. Hough, compiler. Results of a Series of Meteorological Observations, Made in Obedience to Instructions from the Regents of the University, at Sundry Academies in the State of New-York, From 1826 to 1850 Inclusive (Albany, N.Y.: Weed, Parsons and Company), 1855 (Offsite-box RC-17, Volume Spine: New-York Meteorology)
    - Meteorological observations taken at Erasmus Hall Academy, 1852–1869, 1940 (Offsite-box RC-17, Folder Meteorological Reports Made at Erasmus Hall Academy)
      Approximately 35 reports, in manuscript, each covering a one-month period, dated between 1852–1869. These are apparently rough drafts of the records later copied into the 2 folio volumes of reports, except that these volumes cease with 1857.
      Also, correspondence with U.S. Weather Service, 1940.
  - Midwout Magazine
    - The Midwout Magazine, v. 3, no. 5 (Fall and Winter), 1913–1914 (Offsite-box RC-6b, Folder John J. Snyder—historical writings on Flatbush)
  - Monroe, James (President of the U.S.)—Autograph
    - Certificate of passage for "the Ship Carrier of New York," issued by the President of the United States of America, 1818 June 22 (Offsite-box RC-6b, Folder Ship's Papers (James Monroe, J. Q. Adams))
      Signed by James Monroe, President, and John Quincy Adams, Secretary of State.
  - Morrow, Honore Willsie (1880–1940)
    - Letter to Miss Marjorie Weirich, 1928 November 28 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Autographs)
      American historical novelist, author of The Last Full Measure, 1930.
      Holograph letter to Miss Marjorie Weirich, dated "36 Gramercy Park, New York, Nov. 28, 1928," thanking her for letter and informing her that publisher will send "a copy of the picture."
  - Music Books
    - [Vanderveer and Remsen music books], circa 1775–1800 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Music books, late 18th c.)
      • Music book, lacking title page and pp. 1–9, late 18th c., inscribed inside rear cover: "Jane Vanderveer, Ann Vanderveers Book."
      • Read, Daniel. The Columbian harmonist, no. 2, containing... introduction to psalmody... choice collection of sacred music... New Haven: n.d. Inscribed on fly-leaf: "Miss Phoebe Remsen November the 14 1800."
  - Nassau County, New York
    - Paumanacke, A Pageant of Nassau County, Old and New. In Commemoration of the Tercentenary of Nassau County. Jones Beach Stadium, Zachs Bay, Jones Beach State Park [2 copies], 1936 June 19 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Pageant—Nassau Co. Tercentennial)
  - National High School Photographic Awards
    - 11th Annual National High School Photographic Awards, 1956 (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder EHHS—Awards—misc. (folder 2))
      Stephen Garfield of EHHS won honorable mention. A copy of the list of winners and Garfield's photo.
  - Neefus Family
    - Waerachtighe Beschry – Vinghe... (Delft, Holland), 1584 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Dutch book dated 1584)
      Inscribed inside front cover: "Holland Dutch Book 309 years old, Printed and sold at Delft, Date 1584. Loaned by Peter I. Neefus, Flatbush, Kings Co., Long Island. Exhibited by Miss L. G. Zabriskie of same place."
  - New Utrecht
    - "View of the House in New Utrecht, L.I. in which Gen. Nathaniel Woodhull died of his wounds in 1776. This house, built in 1657 by Nicasius de Sille, stood on the spot now occupied by the dwelling of Barnet Wyckoff", 1866 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Brooklyn, N.Y.—General Views)
      Made for Henry McClosky's Manual for 1866. colored lithograph, 8 ½ x 12".
  - New Utrecht Reformed Church
    - Newspaper clipping detailing history of this church, located at 18th Avenue between 83rd and 84th Streets, undated (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Churches)
  - New-York American
    - New-York American, v. 23, no. 4992, 1841 November 4 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Erasmus Hall Academy—Advertisements)
      Includes an advertisement at top of col. 3, p. 1, for Erasmus Hall Academy. This paper was predecessor of the Journal-American. It has fascinating advertisements for railroads, auctions, etc.
  - New York State—Map
    - "A Chorographical Map of the Province of New York in North America... by order of His Excellency Major General William Tryon.. ." (London: William Fadden, engraver), 1779/1849 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder 1779 Map of New York State)
      This is an 1849 reprint of the original [1779], made at Albany by Richard H. Pease. Probably removed from "Documents Relating to the Colonial History of the State of New York" or similar work.
  - Nucleus
    - "The Nucleus," published by the Science Department of Erasmus Hall High School, 1948–1954 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Science Publications including Biota)
      • Vol. 1 (June 1948) [2 copies]
      • Vol. 3 (June 1949)
      • Vol. 4 (Spring 1950)
      • Vol. 5 (June 1952) [2 copies]
      • Vol. 7 (Spring 1954) [2 copies]
  - O'Donoghue Medals
    - List of winners of O'Donoghue Medals, undated (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Awards)
      (Note: the Medals are [were; circa 1972] on display in old trophy case [at EHHS].)
  - Orbis Latinus
    - "Orbis Latinus," published by the Latin students of Erasmus Hall High School, 1955–1957 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Latin publications (Vox Classica, Orbis Latinus))
      • Vol. 1, no. 1 (Fall 1955)
      • Vol. 1, no. 2 (Spring 1956) [2 copies]
      • Vol. 2, no. 1 (Fall 1956)
      • Vol. 2, no. 2 (Spring 1957)
      • Vol. 3, no. 1 (Fall 1957)
  - Oxman, Mrs. Harriet (EHHS principal, 1972–1982)
    - Miscellaneous material, undated (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Mrs. Harriet Oxman, principal, EHHS, 1972–)
  - Pan-American News
    - "The Pan-American News," published by the Pan-American Club of Erasmus Hall High School, 1936 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Pan American Club Publications)
      • Vol. 1, no. 4 (December 1936) [3 copies]
  - Papyrus
    - "Papyrus, the publication of the XYZ Club", 1931–1955 (Offsite-box RC-4b, Volume Papyrus: The First Twenty-Five Years)
      Bound volume containing 1931–1955 complete, given by Mr. and Mrs. M. Gershon in memory of Ruth Levinson Berkowsky.
    - "Papyrus, the publication of the XYZ Club", 1931–1960, 1969 (Offsite-box RC-4b, Folder Papyrus (copy 1))
  - Pensamientos
    - "Pensamientos," published by the Spanish Department of Erasmus Hall High School, 1944 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Spanish Dep't. Publications)
      • Vol. 1, no. 1 (June 1944)
  - Pinnacle
    - "The Pinnacle," published by the class of June 1942, 1940, 1941 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder EHHS—Misc. Publications)
      • Fourth Term issue, Spring 1940
      • Grade Seven issue, Dec. 1941
  - Postillion
    - "Der Postillion," published by the German Department of Erasmus Hall High School, 1930–1937 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Der Postillion)
      • Vol. 1, no. 3 (April 1930) [14 copies]
      • Vol. 1, no. 7 (March 1931)
      • Vol. 3, no. 9 (June 1932)
      • Vol. 5, no. 13 (June 1935)
      • Vol. 6, no. 14 (June 1936) [4 copies]
      • Vol. 8, no. 1 (Jan. 1937)
      • Vol. 8, no. 2 (Dec. 1937)
  - Prensita
    - "La Prensita," published by the Spanish Department of Erasmus Hall High School, 1936 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Spanish Dep't. Publications)
      • Vol. 1, no. 1 (June 1936) [2 copies]
      • Vol. 1, no. 2 (Dec. 1936) [3 copies]
  - Printing—History of
    - Printing—History of, 1300s–1913 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder History of Printing (leaves from original ms. & printed books))
      Gift of Erasmus Hall teacher Miss Marjorie Weirich, consisting of a one-page history of printing and actual leaves from early books:
      1. 14 x 20" parchment page from book which contained the church service (Records Case, Drawer 7, Manuscript folder).
      2. Illuminated ms. of 14th c. by Carthusian monks.
      3. Leaf from book publ. in 1498 by Wynken de Worde on press of William Caxton.
      4. Leaf from The Book of Common Prayer, printed 1762 by John Baskerville, printer to Univ. of Cambridge.
      5. Specimen of finest paper ever made in America, water mark of Dard Hunter, 1913.
      6. Two leaves from book printed in red and black ink in 20th c. by Kelmscott Press, England.
      Also included are three postcards showing early printing, and Miss Weirich's paper, "Pardon My Papyrus."
      Unless otherwise indicated, the above are in Records Case, Drawer 1, folder marked "History of Printing by Miss M. Weirich"
  - Prospect Park
    - [Composition by Alexander C. Snyder], 1868 January 17 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder "Skating in Prospect Park")
    - Simon, Donald E. Historic Prospect Park, Brooklyn, New York, 1974 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Prospect Park)
  - Public Instruction
    - [Laws and circular], 1864, 1867 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Public Instruction, 1864, 1867)
      • Laws of 1864: An Act to Revise and Consolidate the General Acts Relating to Public Instruction. Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co., Printers, 1864. 32 pg.
      • Circular to School District Trustees. 1867. 23 pg. "By Chapter 406 of the Laws of 1867, all rate bills are abolished, and all the Public Schools in the State made FREE from and after October 1st, 1867."
  - Randall, Nancy (Hammond) (?–1816)
    - Silhouette, undated (Offsite-box RC-10a, Folder Original framed silhouette of Nancy, wife of John Randall...)
      Original framed silhouette of Nancy (Hammond) Randall, wife of John Randall of Randell's [sic] Island, New York City. Image size, 3 ¼ x 4 ¼". Frame size, 6 ¼ x 7 ¼". The paper silhouette is backed by black cloth. Wooden frame painted gold.
  - Reaction
    - "Reaction," a Physical Science Journal published by the Physical Science Department, Erasmus Hall High School, 1968 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Science Publications including Biota)
      • Vol. 5, no. 1 (Spring 1968) [2 copies]
  - Reading Boards
    - Three reading boards believed to have been used by Erasmus Hall scholars early in the 19th century, circa 1800–1850 (Offsite-box RC-15, Enclosure "Reading Boards" used by Erasmus Hall scholars)
  - Reformed Dutch Church
    - Het Nieuwe Testament... (Amsterdam), 1696 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope New Testament, Amsterdam, 1696)
      Inscribed inside rear cover "Jeremeas Lott syn boek Anno 1788." With bookplate of Dr. John L. Zabriskie (1831–1895) of Flatbush.
    - The Heidelbergh catechism, or method of instruction, in the Christian religion..., 1764 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Jeremiah Lott's copy of the first English translation of the Heidelbergh)
      The Heidelbergh catechism, or method of instruction, in the Christian religion, as the same is taught in the Reformed churches and schools of Holland. Translated for the use of the Reformed Protestant Dutch Church, of the City of New-York (New York: John Holt, 1764). Jeremiah Lott's copy, with his autograph.
    - Livingston, John H. The psalms and hymns, with the catechism, confession of faith, and liturgy of the Reformed Dutch Church in North America (New Brunswick: Deare & Terhune), 1814 (Offsite-box RC-16, Envelope Psalms and Hymns of the Reformed Dutch Church)
  - Regents of the University of the State of New York
    - [Letter and reply], 1866 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
      • Letter from S. B. Woolworth, Dec. 14, 1866, regarding failure of Academy to submit Annual Report.
      • Draft of reply by J. L. Zabriskie, Secretary, dated Dec. 17, 1866.
    - [Letters and instructions], 1875 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Regents of the University of the State of New York, 1875)
  - Remsen Family
    - Read, Daniel. The Columbian harmonist, no. 2, containing... introduction to psalmody... choice collection of sacred music... (New Haven: n.d.), 1800 November 14 (Offsite-box RC-16)
      Inscribed on fly-leaf: "Miss Phoebe Remsen November the 14 1800."
  - Retort
    - "The Retort," published by the Honorary Chemistry Club of Erasmus Hall High School, 1937–1938 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Science Publications including Biota)
      • Vol. 1, no. 2 (May 14, 1937)
      • Vol. 2, no. 2 (May 11, 1938) [2 copies]
  - Roberts, Kenneth (1885–1957)
    - Letter to John P. Campana, 1954 August 3 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Autographs)
      American historical novelist. Typed, signed letter, dated Aug. 3, 1954, with letterhead "Kenneth Roberts, Kennebunkport, Maine," to Mr. John P. Campana, in which he speaks of "Chronus complex" and Lizzie Bourne.
  - Science Gazette
    - "Science Gazette," magazine of the science clubs of Erasmus Hall High School, 1945–1946 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Science Publications including Biota)
      • Vol. 1, no. 1 (Jan. 1945)
      • Vol. 1, no. 2 (Fall 1946)
  - Sewel, W.
    - Sewel, W. A large dictionary English and Dutch (Amsterdam), 1708 (Offsite-box RC-17, Volume Spine: Woordenboek)
      Inscribed "Cornelius Van Der Veer His Book Anno Dom. 1796."
  - Ship's Papers
    - Certificate of passage for "the Ship Carrier of New York," issued by the President of the United States of America, 1818 June 22 (Offsite-box RC-6b, Folder Ship's Papers (James Monroe, J. Q. Adams))
  - Snyder, Alexander C.
    - [Composition by Alexander C. Snyder], 1868 January 17 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder "Skating in Prospect Park")
  - Spirit of Erasmus
    - "Spirit of Erasmus." Address given by Gregory Weinstein at dedication of final wing, 1940 November 19 (Offsite-box RC-10b, Frame Spirit of Erasmus)
      12 x 18". 13 copies. One framed.
  - Spirit of Flatbush
    - Spirit of Flatbush, v. 1, no. 1 (Dec. 1971) – v. 3, no. 1 (1976), 1971–1976 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Committee to Preserve Flatbush Town Hall)
      Complete run. No more published. Issued by Committee to Preserve Flatbush Town Hall, and the Town of Flatbush Civil and Cultural Association, Inc. (TOFCCA).
  - Sports Review
    - Sports Review [a student newspaper], 1936, 1938 (Offsite-box RC-9a, Folder EHHS—Athletics—Publications, etc. folder #1)
      Of the same format as the Dutchman, but with strictly sports-oriented news.
      • v. 1, no. 1 (June 10, 1936)
      • v. 3, no. 1 (June 3, 1938)
  - Strong, Robert Grier (Erasmus Hall Academy principal, 1879–1892)
    - [Letters and report], 1874 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
      • Holograph letter by Strong, dated March 18, 1874, in which he sets fort conditions under which he will accept.
      • Report of committee appointed to find new principal for Academy, choosing Strong. Dated March 25, 1874.
      • Holograph letter by Strong, dated Apr. 20, 1874, accepting appointment as principal.
    - [Letter submitting Annual Report for 1887–88], 1888 April 10 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
      Holograph letter signed by Strong, dated Apr. 10, 1888, submitting Annual Report for 1887–88 to Trustees of Academy. 6 pg. letter, 2 pg. report.